We can extend policy-based methods to cover
我们可以将基于策略的方法扩展到
large and continuous state spaces by using a function to approximate the policy,
涵盖大型连续性状态空间 方法是使用一个函数来估算策略
just like value function approximation.
就像值函数逼近一样
To do this, we parameterize the policy with theta,
为此 我们用 θ 参数化策略
which can be the weights of a neural network or some other model.
θ 可以是神经网络或其他模型的权重
Our goal would then be to optimize these parameters to find the best policy.
我们的目标变成优化这些参数 以便找到最佳策略
One simple approximation function is the Linear combination of features.
一个简单的近似函数是这些特征的线性组合
But since we want our ultimate output to be
但是因为我们希望最终输出
a probability distribution that we can sample actions from,
是一个可以从中抽样的概率分布
we need to use some transformation.
因此需要进行一些转换
For example, we can apply the Softmax Function which exponentiates
例如 我们可以应用 Softmax 函数
the Linear combination result and then normalizes it
该函数通过除以所有动作的指数之和
by dividing by the sum of exponentials for all actions.
指数化线性组合的结果并使其标准化
This produces a set of action probability values that sum to one.
这样可以形成一组和为 1 的动作概率值
Note that this only works for a discrete set of actions.
注意 这种转换仅适用于一组离散的动作
For example, the mountain car environment in OpenAI,
例如 OpenAI 中的山地车环境
has two continuous state variables, position and velocity.
有两个连续性状态变量 即位置和速度
And a discrete action space with three actions,
以及一个离散动作空间
zero to push left,
其中包含三个动作 0 表示向左推动
one for no push and two to push right.
1 表示不推动 2 表示向右推动
You can model the car's behavior with a Softmax Policy and learn to optimize it.
你可以使用 Softmax 策略对汽车的行为进行建模并学会优化它
But there is also a version with
但是还可以有采用单个连续动作变量的版本
a single continuous action variable that can take negative values to push left,
负值表示向左推动
zero for no push,
0 表示不推动
or positive to push right.
正值表示向右推动
This is more realistic and it affords greater flexibility in taking actions,
这样更现实 并且采取的动作更加灵活
but it is also more challenging because of the continuous action space.
但是也更有挑战性 因为动作空间是连续的
When we have an environment with a continuous action space,
当环境具有连续动作空间时
we can use a Gaussian Policy.
我们可以使用高斯策略
That is, we sample actions from a Gaussian or
即从高斯或正态分布中抽取动作
normal distribution where the parameters
该分布的参数
of the distribution are determined by our features.
由我们的特征决定
For example, the mean mu,
例如 均值 μ 可以是
can be our simple linear combination of features and the variance
特征的简单线性组合
sigma squared can be fixed or parameterized in a similar way.
σ2 可以是固定的值或以类似的方式参数化
We can apply the same trick to any approximation function that produces
我们可以对任何近似函数应用相同的技巧
some values and turn them into probabilities that represent a stochastic policy.
这些函数会生成一些值并将这些值变成表示随机性策略的概率
Now, how do we decide which policy is the best?
如何判断哪个策略是最佳策略？
We need some objective measure that tells us how good a policy is,
我们需要一些目标衡量方法来判断某个策略的效果如何
and it needs to be a function of the policy parameters.
该衡量方法必须是策略参数的函数
Intuitively, this needs to capture
凭直觉判断
the expected value of rewards obtained under that policy.
该函数需要捕获根据该策略获得的奖励的预期值
Let's introduce the idea of a trajectory, tau,
我们来介绍下轨线 τ 这一概念
which you can think of as a complete or partial episode.
可以将其看做一个完整或部分阶段
Thus, the expected value can be computed by sampling over multiple trajectories.
因此 可以通过对多个轨线抽样计算预期值
Now, if you have an episodic task at hand.
如果你有一个阶段性任务
Then one option is to use the mean of the return from the first time step G1.
那么一种方式是使用第一个时间步 G1 的回报均值
That is, the cumulative discounted rewards for the entire episode.
即整个阶段的累积折扣回报
This is equivalent to the value of the starting state.
等同于起始状态的值
In continuing environments, we can't rely on a specific start state,
在连续环境中 我们不能依赖于特定的起始状态
so it's better to tie the objective to a measure that is not dependent on that.
因此最好将目标与不依赖于这种状态的衡量方法相关联
One such measure is the average or expected state value.
一种此类衡量方法是平均或预期状态值
Intuitively, you want to prefer a policy that leads to a higher average.
凭直觉来看 你希望选择一个使平均值更高的策略
But some states may occur more often than others.
但是某些状态的发生频率可能高于其他状态
So each state value now needs to be weighted
因此现在 每个状态值需要
by the probability of occurrence of the respective state,
用相应状态的发生概率进行加权
that is, it stationary probability.
即平稳概率
You can calculate this by dividing the number of occurrences of the state,
计算方法是将状态的发生次数除以
by the total number of occurrences of all states.
所有状态的总发生次数
A related measure is the average action value,
相关衡量方法是以类似方式
or Q value, calculated in a similar way.
计算的平均动作值或 Q 值
But remember that the goal of encoding the policy directly,
但是注意直接对策略进行编码的目标是
is so that we don't have to keep track of state values or action values.
不需要记录状态值或动作值
So, a measure that we can compute directly,
因此我们可以直接计算的衡量指标是
is the average reward at each time step.
每个时间步的平均奖励
The interesting thing, is that all these formulations
有趣的是 所有这些公式在优化策略方面
seem to work equally well for optimizing policies.
似乎都可以取得相同的良好效果
Which objective you choose,
选择哪个目标
depends on the nature of the problem or environment.
取决于问题或环境的特性
Pick whichever is the most convenient to compute and
你可以选择最方便计算
best reflects the true objective you're aiming for.
并且最能体现你要实现的目标的公式